A Guide to the Joseph Sobek Papers 1980.0039
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
Joseph Sobek Papers
undated, 1951-1981
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
1980.0039
7.5 Linear Feet
Joseph George Sobek was born 5 April 1918, in Greenwich, Connecticut and was raised there. He served in the Marines and later became a police detective. Until he retired in 1985, he had spent most of his life as a tennis and squash racquets professional at the Greenwich Country Club. He died of congenital heart disease March 27, 1998. Sobek was the first person inducted into the Racquetball Hall of Fame.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated in 1980 by Mr. Sobek.
Arrangement
Series I: Subject Files (undated, 1959-1981) contains newspaper clippings and magazine articles relating to Sobek's role as the creator and developer of racquetball. The series also includes samples of original rule booklets, clippings from the first National Paddle Rackets Tournament, the patent application for the racket [9 March 1950], photographs and the blueprint for the first racquetball racket.
Series II: Correspondence (1951-1980) contains correspondence to and from municipal recreation departments, YMCAs, health clubs, school, the National Paddle Racquet Corporation, and the Magnan Company. The bulk of the correspondence is with various organizations and clubs, particularly YMCAs, interested in ordering equipment or acquiring information about the game's rules. The series is arranged chronologically.
Series III: Geographical Files (circa 1958-1967) consists of orders and invoices. The series is arranged alphabetically by the name of the city in which the order originated.
Series IV: Racquet and Ball (undated) contains an official "Joe Sobek Paddle Racket" ball and the original Magnan Company paddle racquet.
Biography
Joseph George Sobek was born 5 April 1918, in Greenwich, Connecticut, and was raised there. He served in the Marines and later became a police detective. Until he retired in 1985, he had spent most of his life as a tennis and squash racquets professional at the Greenwich Country Club. He died of congenital heart disease 27 March 27 1998. Sobek was the first person inducted into the Racquetball Hall of Fame.
Joe Sobek had been a squash and tennis professional for seven years before he invented Racquetball at the Greenwich, Connecticut, YMCA in 1950.
The idea of inventing a paddle racquetball game struck him when he found it difficult to get a regular competitive squash partner and was not satisfied with handball, a game he considered too strenuous and resulted in sore palms. Working at the time as a rubber manufacturer, Sobek felt that his job did not provide adequate exercise. He began looking for a game that would provide an adequate workout and as fun as squash and handball. Paddleball was ideal for him, if only he could use a racket instead of a traditional paddle. So he fashioned his ideal racquet from a badminton racquet design and a matched ball from a tennis ball, without the fuzz. At the same time, Sobek began developing the rules for his new athletic activity.
Once he had developed a plan for rules, Sobek took his draft and design to Magnan Racket Manufacturing Company in Massachusetts. The firm attempted to follow his specifications and failed in the first few attempts before they successfully created the first racquet in 1951.
The game was accepted and played in the YMCA circles initially. By the 1970s, it had spread to other facilities and its growing popularity was enhanced due to the simplicity of the game and the strong workout provided in a short period of playing time. Today is has become an Olympic sport, with two major racquetball associations—International Racquetball Association (IRA) and American Racquetball Association (ARA)—as well as numerous clubs all over the world.
Scope and Content
The papers are arranged in four series detailing the international acceptance of racquetball. Documents include correspondence, newspaper clippings, articles, rulebooks, legal and financial records, and an official "Joe Sobek paddle racket" ball and the original Magnan Company paddle racquet.
Bibliography
Additional information on the history of racquetball is available here.
Sports; Inventors; Regulations (executive records); Patents; Financial Records; United States (nation); Connecticut (state); Athletic clubs; Athletics; Recreation agencies; Administrative records; Correspondence; Magnan Racket Corporation; National Paddle Racquet Corporation; Greenwich YMCA (Greenwich, Conn.)
- Series 1: Subject Files, undated, 1959-1981
  - Advertisement (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Content Note
    For the Paddle Racket to "Mr. Physical Director"
  - American Racquetball Association (ARA), undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Brochure and letter to Sobek from James H. Peters, President of American Racquetball Association inviting the club the "opportunity to join the American Racquetball Association."
  - Back Bay Racquet Club—Agnew, Jack, 1979-1980 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Correspondence, notes publications associated with the Back Bay Racquet Club and its opening in Boston.
  - Dreyfus Fund, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Promotional letter and attachments inviting investment.
  - Dunhill Racquet, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Telephone messages and brochures with prices lists.
  - Ford, G. William, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Correspondence and contracts regarding career management.
  - General Sportcraft, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Invoices and receipts f0r paddle balls.
  - Correspondence from individuals, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Queries for rules, paddles, balls
  - International Racquetball Association (IRA), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Correspondence regarding cover article for Racquetball Magazine.
  - Correspondence and invoices, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Correspondence documents arrangements between Sobek and "Gabe," who is making contacts and distributing paddles and balls in California. Invoices document sales in other states.
  - Publications, 1956-1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Correspondence, ad copy Journal of Physical Education issues: v. 51 # 4, March-April 1954; v. 57 #5, May-June 1960; v. 58 #3, January-February 1961; v. 59 # 2 November-December 1961; v. 58 #4 March-April 1961. Nutmeg News v. 1 #1 August-October 1953
  - National Paddle Racket Association, undated, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Rules, application for membership and "Mr. Physical Director" letter
  - National Tournament, 1956, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Concord Hotel (New York) and YMCA (Cleveland, OH)
    - YMCA Tournament [first], 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Correspondence with YMCA
  - News articles, 1959-1980
    - Joe Sobek, 1959, 1978-1980 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Photocopies of newspaper clippings and articles.
    - Joe Sobek—Memphis Trip, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Photocopy of newspaper article and flier announcing dedication program for the Leslie Stratton YMCA's new courts.
  - Paddle Racket, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Handwritten and typed notes about the physical benefits and rules of paddle racquet.
  - Patent application, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Correspondence with patent attorney, sketch of paddle and patent attorney "application."
  - Pepsi Cola—Sobek, Joe, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Sponsorship correspondence.
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
    8 8 x 10 B&W prints
  - Playing rules and regulations, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Copies of 2 editions (white and blue)
  - P.M. Magazine—Krubski, John, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Notes, telephone messages and poster regarding New York OPen Racquetball Championship.
  - Promotional literature, 1956-1964 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    By Laws document, Paddle racquests flier, correspondence, Yankee News (September-October 1963).
  - Racquetball
    - Clubs, undated, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Correspondence and brochures (Winning Walls, Four Seasons).
    - General, 1976-1980 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Notes Publications: The Greenwich Review v. 33 #1 January 1980 Racquetball v. 5 #5 September-October 1976, v. 8 #1 January-February 1979 New England Tennis Journal & Racquetball Northeast v. 6 # 11 December 1979
  - Racquetball illustrated, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Correspondence regarding article about Sobek and requesting extra issues.
  - Requests for tournaments, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Correspondence and Squash and Racquets Magazine v. 6 #2 October 1967, v. 7 #1 January 1968. Correspondence not necessarily regarding tournaments; other topics include requests for rules, supplies, etc.
  - Rules and publication (Box 2)
    - Handball, Paddleball and Squash (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Paddle Racket (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Spiegal, Jim (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Sports Illustrated (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - VA Insurance (Box 2, Folder 32)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1951-1980
  - 1951 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 1952 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1953 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 1954 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 1955 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 1956 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - 1957 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - 1958 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - 1959 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - 1960 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - 1961 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - 1962 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - 1963 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - 1964 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - 1965 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - 1966 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - 1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - 1968 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - 1969 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - 1971 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - 1977 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - 1978 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - 1979 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - 1980 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Series III: Geographical Files, circa 1958-1967
  - Akron, Ohio—Akron Jewish Center (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Albany, New York—Slaman, Al (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Albuquerque, New Mexico—Yorgiadis, Alex (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Ann Arbor, Michigan—University of Michigan (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - Augusta, Georgia—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - Alliance, Ohio—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Anchorage, Alaska (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Ansonia, Connecticut—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Asbury Park, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Atlanta, Georgia
    - Athletic Club (Box 4, Folder 66)
    - Emory University (Box 4, Folder 67)
    - YMCA (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Aurora, Illinois—Arney, Kent (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - Austin, Texas (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Baltimore, Maryland—Jewish Community Center (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Batavia, New York—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Beaver Dam, Wisconsin
    - Baier, Edward (Box 4, Folder 73)
    - YMCA (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Beaumont, Texas—First Baptist Church (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - Beloit, Wisconsin—Hagadone, Web (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Benton Harbor, Michigan—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 77)
  - Berea, Kentucky—Berea College (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Bergenfield, New Jersey
    - General Sportcraft, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 79)
    - Sportcraft (Box 4, Folder 80)
  - Beverly, Massachusetts
    - Cor-Nix Rubber Company (Box 4, Folder 81)
    - YMCA (Box 4, Folder 82)
  - Boston, Massachusetts—YMCA, Huntington Avenue Branch (Box 4, Folder 83)
  - Brea, California—IMER (Box 4, Folder 84)
  - Bridgeport, Connecticut—Jewish Community Center (Box 4, Folder 85)
  - Brockton, Massachusetts—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 86)
  - Brookfield, Illinois—Wilson & Taurides, Inc. (Box 4, Folder 87)
  - Brooklyn, New York—YMCA, Central Branch (Box 4, Folder 88)
  - Buffalo, New York
    - Jewish Center (Box 4, Folder 89)
    - YMCA (Box 4, Folder 90)
  - Buffalo, Pennsylvania—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 91)
  - Butler, Pennsylvania—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 92)
  - Cambridge, Massachusetts—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 93)
  - Cary, North Carolina
    - Mochrie, R.D. (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Whitehurst, Edward (Box 4, Folder 95)
  - Charleston, South Carolina—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 96)
  - Charlottesville, Virginia (Box 4, Folder 97)
  - Charleston, West Virginia—YMCA (Box 4, Folder 98)
  - Chattanooga, Tennessee—Jones, George W. (Box 4, Folder 99)
  - Chicago, Illinois (Box 5)
    - Chicago Boys Clubs (Box 5, Folder 100)
    - YMCA
      - Joseph Duncan Branch (Box 5, Folder 101)
      - Lincoln Belmot Branch (Box 5, Folder 102)
      - 19 S. LaSalle Street (Box 5, Folder 103)
      - Ravenswood Department (Box 5, Folder 104)
  - Chihuahua, Mexico (Box 5, Folder 105)
  - Cincinnati, Ohio—YMCA, Central Parkway Branch (Box 5, Folder 106)
  - Clayton, Missouri (Box 5, Folder 107)
  - Cleveland, Ohio
    - Bleep-Coombs Sporting (Box 5, Folder 108)
    - Champion Sporting Goods (Box 5, Folder 109)
    - Cleveland Sport Shop (Box 5, Folder 110)
    - Cleveland State University (Box 5, Folder 111)
    - Downtown Club (Box 5, Folder 112)
    - Fenn College (Box 5, Folder 113)
    - Jack's Jewelry & Appliances (Box 5, Folder 114)
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 5, Folder 115)
    - Olympic Sport Goods (Box 5, Folder 116)
    - Simpson, C. (Box 5, Folder 117)
    - Stones Downtown Club (Box 5, Folder 118)
    - YMCA
      - Addison Road Branch (Box 5, Folder 119)
      - Broadway Branch (Box 5, Folder 120)
      - Brooklyn/Parma Branch (Box 6, Folder 121)
      - Central Branch (Box 6, Folder 122)
      - University Circle Branch (Box 6, Folder 123)
      - West Side Branch (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Clinton, Iowa—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 125)
  - Columbus, Georgia (Box 6, Folder 126)
  - Columbus, Ohio
    - Businessmen's Athletic Club (Box 6, Folder 127)
    - Crestview Presbyterian Church (Box 6, Folder 128)
    - Jewish Center (Box 6, Folder 129)
    - Ohio-West Virginia Area Council (Box 6, Folder 130)
    - Simpson, Cyril (Box 6, Folder 131)
    - YMCA, Metropolitan YMCA (Box 6, Folder 132)
  - Connersville, Indiana—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 133)
  - Corpus Christi, Texas—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 134)
  - Dallas, Texas
    - Fry, Hayden (Box 6, Folder 135)
    - Southern Methodist University (Box 6, Folder 136)
  - Danville, Illinois (Box 6, Folder 137)
  - Danville, Virginia
    - Carmichael, Mack (Box 6, Folder 138)
    - YMCA (Box 6, Folder 139)
  - Dearborn, Michigan—YMCA, Dearborn Branch (Box 6, Folder 140)
  - Des Moines, Iowa
    - Drake University (Box 6, Folder 141)
    - YMCA (Box 6, Folder 142)
  - Detroit, Michigan
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 6, Folder 143-144)
    - Sidney-Hill Northwest Club (Box 6, Folder 145)
    - Walters, Arthur (Box 6, Folder 146)
  - Dubuque, Iowa—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 147)
  - Duluth, Minnesota—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 148)
  - Edmonton, Alberta—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 149)
  - Elizabeth, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 150)
  - El Paso, Texas—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 151)
  - Flint, Michigan—Mullin Company (Box 6, Folder 152)
  - Fort Bragg, North Carolina (Box 6, Folder 153)
  - Fort Huachuca, Arizona (Box 6, Folder 154)
  - Fort Monmouth, New Jersey (Box 6, Folder 155)
  - Fort Pierce, Florida—Shaw, Jerry (Box 6, Folder 156)
  - Fort Wadsworth, Staten Island, New York (Box 6, Folder 157)
  - Fort Wayne, Indiana—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 158)
  - Galveston, Texas—YMCA (Box 6, Folder 159)
  - Garrison, New York—Garrison Club (Box 6, Folder 160)
  - Geneva, Ohio—True Tempor Corporation (Box 6, Folder 161)
  - Glen Oak, New York—Hillside Hospital (Box 7, Folder 162)
  - Goldsboro, North Carolina—Music & Sports Inc. (Box 7, Folder 163)
  - Grand Island, Nebraska—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 164)
  - Granville, Ohio
    - Denison University—Olcott, Jack (Box 7, Folder 165)
    - George Hardware (Box 7, Folder 166)
  - Green Bay, Wisconsin—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 167)
  - Greensboro, North Carolina—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 168)
  - Greensburg, Pennsylvania—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 169)
  - Greenwich, Connecticut
    - Fairview Printers (Box 7, Folder 170)
    - The Sport Shop (Box 7, Folder 171)
    - YMCA (Box 7, Folder 172)
  - Hackensack, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 173)
  - Hamilton, New York—Colgate University (Box 7, Folder 174)
  - Hamilton, Ohio—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 175)
  - Hartford, Connecticut
    - Friedman, Myron (Box 7, Folder 176)
    - Keene's Sport Shop (Box 7, Folder 177)
    - Sport Center, Inc. (Box 7, Folder 178)
    - YMCA (Box 7, Folder 179)
  - Harvey, Illinois—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 180)
  - Haverhill, Massachusetts—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 181)
  - High Point, North Carolina—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 182)
  - Highland Park, Michigan—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 183)
  - Holyoke, Massachusetts—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 184)
  - Honolulu, Hawaii—Parker, Dr. R. J. (Box 7, Folder 185)
  - Houston, Texas (Box 7, Folder 186)
  - Indiana, Pennsylvania—State Teachers College (Box 7, Folder 187)
  - Indianapolis, Indiana
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 7, Folder 188)
    - Metropolitan YMCA (Box 7, Folder 189)
    - Nichols, N. (Box 7, Folder 190)
    - Thacker, Lee (Box 7, Folder 191)
  - Ithaca, New York (Box 7, Folder 192)
  - Joliet, Illinois—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 193)
  - Kanapolis, North Carolina—YMCA (Box 7, Folder 194)
  - Klamath Falls, Oregon—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 195)
  - Knoxville, Tennessee—University of Tennessee (Box 8, Folder 196)
  - Kokomo, Indiana—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 197)
  - Lake Charles, Louisiana
    - Mervis, Mike (Box 8, Folder 198)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 199)
  - Lancaster, Pennsylvania—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 200)
  - Las Vegas, Nevada—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 201)
  - Lawrence, Massachusetts
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 8, Folder 202)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 203)
  - LeGrange, Connecticut—Deal, Donald L. (Box 8, Folder 204)
  - Levittown, Pennsylvania (Box 8, Folder 205)
  - Lexington, Kentucky—University of Kentucky (Box 8, Folder 206)
  - Lima, Ohio—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 207)
  - Lincoln, Nebraska—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 208)
  - Little Rock, Arkansas—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 209)
  - Los Angeles, California—State of California (Box 8, Folder 210)
  - Louisville, Kentucky
    - Consolidated Tire Company (Box 8, Folder 211)
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 8, Folder 212-213)
    - Porco, Ken (Box 8, Folder 214)
    - Puritan Cordage Mills (Box 8, Folder 215)
    - YMCA, Central Branch (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - Lubbock, Texas—Texas Tech College (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Madison, Wisconsin
    - Oscar Meyer & Company (Box 8, Folder 218)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - Manchester, New Hampshire—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Mansfield, Ohio—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Marion, Ohio—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 222)
  - Maxwell Air Force Base, Alabama (Box 8, Folder 223)
  - McGuire Air Force Base, New Jersey (Box 8, Folder 224)
  - Memphis, Tennessee—YMCA, Leslie M. Stratton Branch (Box 8, Folder 225)
  - Meriden, Connecticut
    - Burns, J.J. (Box 8, Folder 226)
    - Burt, Gary T. (Box 8, Folder 227)
    - Meriden Boys' Club (Box 8, Folder 228)
    - Rinaldi's (Box 8, Folder 229)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 230)
  - Michigan City, Indiana—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 231)
  - Middletown, Ohio—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 232)
  - Midland, Texas—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 233)
  - Moose Jaw, Saskatchewan—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 234)
  - Nashua, New Hampshire—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 235)
  - Nashville, Tennessee
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 8, Folder 236)
    - T.R. Hiett Sporting Goods (Box 8, Folder 237)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 238)
  - Natchitoches, Louisiana (Box 8, Folder 239)
  - Newburgh, New York—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 240)
  - New Britain, Connecticut
    - Boyea, Doug (Box 8, Folder 241)
    - YMCA (Box 8, Folder 242-243)
  - New Brunswick, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 8, Folder 244)
  - New Haven, Connecticut
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 8, Folder 245)
    - YMCA (New Milford, CT) (Box 8, Folder 246)
    - Canterbury School (Box 8, Folder 247)
    - Cramer & Anderson (Box 8, Folder 248)
  - New Paltz, New York—State University College (Box 10, Folder 249)
  - New Westminster, British Columbia—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 250)
  - New York, New York
    - Alex Taylor & Company (Box 10, Folder 251)
    - Anderson, J.W. (Box 10, Folder 252)
    - Farman, Joe (Box 10, Folder 253)
    - Goldsmith Brothers (Box 10, Folder 254)
    - Health Roof Club, Foley, E.H. (Box 10, Folder 255)
    - Hirchorn, Fred (Box 10, Folder 256)
    - Lecakes, Chris (Box 10, Folder 257)
    - National Jewish Welfare Board (Box 10, Folder 258)
    - YMCA
      - Harlem Branch (Box 10, Folder 259)
      - National Council (Box 10, Folder 260)
      - National Office, New York (Box 10, Folder 261)
      - West Side Branch (Box 10, Folder 262)
  - Newark, Delaware
    - Breslin, William (Box 10, Folder 263)
    - University of Delaware (Box 10, Folder 264)
  - Newark, New Jersey—YMCA, Downtown Branch (Box 10, Folder 265)
  - North Attleboro, Massachusetts
    - Magnan (Box 10, Folder 266)
    - Magnan Corporation (Box 10, Folder 267)
  - Norwich, Connecticut—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 268)
  - Norwich, New York—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 269)
  - Notre Dame, Indiana (Box 10, Folder 270)
  - Nyack, New York—Rockland YMCA (Box 10, Folder 271)
  - Oak Park, Illinois—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 272)
  - Oakland, California—YMCA, Central Branch (Box 10, Folder 273)
  - Ogden, Utah—Desert Gym (Box 10, Folder 274)
  - Oklahoma—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 275)
  - Omaha, Nebraska—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 276)
  - Oneonta, New York—State University College of Education (Box 10, Folder 277)
  - Orange, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 278)
  - Orlando, Florida—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 279)
  - Parkersburg, West Virginia—YMCA (Box 10, Folder 280)
  - Parma, Ohio
    - Parma Public Schools (Box 10, Folder 281)
    - Sportcenter, Inc. (Box 10, Folder 282)
  - Pawtucket, Rhode Island
    - Bancroft (Box 10, Folder 283-285)
    - YMCA (Box 10, Folder 286)
  - Pensacola, Florida (Box 11)
    - Balnicky, Robert G. (Box 11, Folder 287)
    - YMCA (Box 11, Folder 288)
  - Philadelphia, Pennsylvania
    - Broadwood Health Institute (Box 11, Folder 289)
    - Collins, Phil (Box 11, Folder 290)
    - Passon's Sport Center (Box 11, Folder 291)
    - University of Pennsylvania (Box 11, Folder 292)
    - YMCA
      - Central Branch (Box 11, Folder 293)
      - Christian Street Branch (Box 11, Folder 294)
  - Phoenix, Arizona
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 11, Folder 295)
    - YMCA (Box 11, Folder 296)
  - Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania
    - Downtown YMCA (Box 11, Folder 297)
    - Point Park Junior College (Box 11, Folder 298)
    - YMCA, Hilltop Branch (Box 11, Folder 299)
  - Pittsfield, Massachusetts—YMCA (Box 11, Folder 300)
  - Plainfield, New Jersey—YMCA (Box 11, Folder 301)
  - Port Chester, New York
    - Jewish Community Center (Box 11, Folder 302)
    - YMCA (Box 11, Folder 303)
  - Provo, Utah (Box 11, Folder 304)
  - Raleigh, North Carolina
    - King, R.H. (Box 11, Folder 305)
    - Simon, Stan (Box 11, Folder 306)
    - Thomas, Jack (Box 11, Folder 307)
    - YMCA (Box 11, Folder 308)
  - Reading, Pennsylvania—Kagen's Inc. (Box 11, Folder 309)
  - Redlands, California—YMCA (Box 11, Folder 310)
  - Regina, Saskatchewan—YMCA (Box 11, Folder 311)
  - Richmond, Kentucky—Eastern Kentucky State College (Box 12, Folder 312)
  - Richmond, Virginia
    - Hooker, T.H. (Box 12, Folder 313)
    - YMCA (Box 12, Folder 314-315)
  - Rochester, New York—Rochester Athletic Club (Box 12, Folder 316)
  - Rochester, Minnesota—YMCA (Box 12, Folder 317)
  - Rocky River, Ohio—Executive Club West (Box 12, Folder 318)
  - Salt Lake City, Utah—YMCA (Box 12, Folder 319)
  - San Diego, California
    - San Diego City School (Box 12, Folder 320)
    - San Diego Club (Box 12, Folder 321)
    - San Diego Rowing Club (Box 12, Folder 322)
    - Stone, Dan (Box 12, Folder 323)
    - YMCA (Box 12, Folder 324)
  - San Francisco, California
    - Concordia-Argonaut (Box 12, Folder 325)
    - Whitney, Everette R. (Box 12, Folder 326)
  - San Mateo, California—College of San Mateo (Box 12, Folder 327)
  - Schenectady, New York—Goldstock's Sporting (Box 12, Folder 328)
  - Seattle, Washington—Ehrlichman, John D. (Box 12, Folder 329)
  - Sewickley, Pennsylvania—YMCA (Box 12, Folder 330)
  - Seymour Johnson Air Force Base, North Carolina (Box 12, Folder 331)